rewardingpanel.com 2016-03-14

# Privacy Policy

Ipsos Stat FZ - LLC is a company registered in the UAE. Ipsos Stat is part of the Ipsos worldwide group of companies. This privacy policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you when you join our on-line panel, take part in surveys, or use the panel members website.

We offer a refer-a-friend feature on our websites, which enables existing members of our panel to invite their friends to join the panel. This process allows the member to enter their friend’s first name and email address into our system, which then sends an automated email message to the friend's email address which includes the registration link to join their panel. As a result, we may obtain your first name and email address from an existing panel member who has asked us to send you an invitation to join the panel. All automated email messages sent to the friend’s email address will include an opt-out link to allow the friend to opt-out of receiving any further emails from us. We limit the number of referrals to five (5) per month.

We collect the information you provide by email and in completing our recruitment questionnaire, when you decide to join our panel.

We collect your Facebook basic profile information (meaning your name, e-mail address, and gender) that you have consented to our using when you connect to, and use the Rewarding Panel Facebook Application within your Facebook account, or you use the “Join using Facebook” or “Login with Facebook” buttons on the panel website.

  * Keep a record of all panel members.
  * Send you invitations to participate in surveys that are relevant to you based on the information you provided in response to our recruitment questionnaire(s).
  * Append personal information about you to your responses to any surveys you participate in, such as geographical location, ethnicity, and occupation categories, etc. for the purpose of analyzing the survey responses and producing anonymous, statistical research results.
  * Enter you into any prize draws that you are eligible to take part in or, where invited to do so, have asked to be entered into.
  * With your explicit consent when asked in a survey, to pass your individual survey responses together with your personal information to the client who commissioned the survey. The client will use this information only for research purposes as explained in the survey. The client may also use this information to contact you in order to invite your participation in further research they conduct, but only where you have been informed of this and have explicitly consented to your information being used by the client for this purpose.
  * To create anonymous, statistical profiles of panel membership based on the information provided by panel members.
  * With your consent, to pass your information to other Ipsos Group companies so that they may invite you to participate in research studies they are carrying out that may be relevant to you.

We may also provide your personal information to:

* Other Ipsos Group companies involved in the research studies we carry out.
* Our sub-contractors who may carry out some of the work we do on our behalf, and under our control, including the service providers who host or provide technical support for our systems. Our sub-contractors are required to abide by the same data privacy legal requirements and security arrangements as ourselves.

This may involve transferring your personal information to other countries, however we can reassure you that we take great care to ensure any transfers are carried out securely and in compliance with all applicable data protection and data privacy legal requirements.

We will NEVER use your information for any purpose other than research. We will NOT try to sell you anything, nor use your information for marketing purposes. Nor will we ever pass your information to third parties for marketing purposes.

For more information about our panels, panel membership, or information related to your membership of one of our panels, please contact our Panel Support Team. They can be contacted by:

Email sent to: [ panelksa@rewardingpanel.com](mailto:panelksa@rewardingpanel.com)

Or by letter sent to:

> Panel Support Team Rewarding Panel PO BOX: 71283, Dubai, UAE 

#### 3\. Children

For any panels or surveys aimed at children, we will always seek consent from a parent, legal guardian, or other person legally responsible for the child before inviting them to join a panel or take part in the research.

#### 4\. Use of Cookies and similar code

By joining our online research panel and taking part in our online research, you agree to our use of cookies and the collection of information from your PC/Laptop or other computing device you may use whilst taking part in our online research activities as outlined below.

Our panel website and online surveys collect information through the use of 'cookies'. These are small files stored on your computer. Further details of what cookies are can be found by visiting [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

The cookies that may be used in connection with this panel are as follows:

Site/Domain/Host | Cookie Name | Purpose of cookie  
---|---|---  
www.rewardingpanel.com | ASP.NET_SessionId | This is set for all users of the website to distinguish you from other users and to help users log into the site.  
ViewPoll | Used to identify unique participant when you use the POLL system on our website. It is used to ensure the same person votes only once in the website poll; it is placed when you vote using the POLL function.  
language | Indicates selected language to be used when viewing the site content.  
utmb | These "Google Analytics" cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. Further details can be found here: http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html  
utmc  
utmz  
Cookie | This cookie is essential for our online surveys to function correctly. It is only set for those surveys.  
RVIDExtId | These cookies are used to store the unique codes produced using digital fingerprinting. This is used as part of our systems to uniquely identify online survey participants and for essential quality control purposes. Please see the "Digital Fingerprinting" information below for more information.  
ISIStest  
JSESSIONID | Used to maintain a session on the social community.  
SOCIAL-{ENVIRONMENT} | Used to maintain the community environment.  
PanelistID | It contains Panelist ID value, and it is used for the current website user. For example: 1303426.  
PanelistSelectedCulture | Contains language and country info for the current website user. For example: en-SA.  
EncryptedPID | Contains encrypted Panelist ID + Panel ID for the current website user.  
F5_REGION | Both cookies are used for the redirect to a specific country's website home page. Valid values for these cookies are "NA" or "EMEA".  
ISAY_OVERRIDE  
ipsosinteractive.com | PJfNXlqz | This cookie is used to balance the load between our servers and so improve the performance of our online surveys.  
RVIDExtId | These cookies are used to store the unique codes produced using digital fingerprinting. This is used as part of our systems to uniquely identify online survey participants and for essential quality control purposes. Please see the "Digital Fingerprinting" information below for more information.  
ISIStest  
  
It is possible for you to delete 'cookies' or to prevent their use by adjusting the browser settings on your computer. However, if you do prevent our online surveys and Panel Members website from using cookies, our surveys and Panel Members website will not work properly, and you will not be able to participate in this Panel.

We may also read cookies placed when you visit other websites to see if you have visited the website of, or been exposed to advertising placed on websites by of one of our clients. With your prior consent, we may also place some cookies on your machine that will allow our partners to identify you as one of our panelists whilst visiting websites for the purpose of replacing one or more of the normal adverts normally displayed on that site for the purpose of testing new advertising material. The cookies that would be used for this purpose are:

Site/Domain/Host | Cookie Name | Purpose of cookie  
---|---|---  
ipsosinteractive.com  
Panel | With your prior consent, these cookies are used to check if you have been exposed to certain online adverts, and in some cases to change the advertising displayed to you, including video any advertising, as you visit sites so that we can test different online advertising material. You can withdraw your consent to this at any time by writing to [ panelksa@rewardingpanel.com](mailto:panelksa@rewardingpanel.com).  
TDCPM  
TDID  
UTID  
UTPROFILES  
BCSI-CS-55f0753225a53952  
a  
a1  
ac  
b  
e  
f  
j  
j1  
o  
p  
r  
s1  
t  
u  
v  
  
Some on-line surveys collect information through the use of 'cookies'. These are small files stored on your computer. These files are used as sparingly as possible and only for quality control, validation and, more importantly, to prevent us sending you reminders for any on-line survey you have already completed. It is possible for you to delete 'cookies' or to prevent their use by adjusting the browser settings on your computer.

In addition to our use of cookies, our online surveys automatically capture information about your IP Address, operating system, screen display settings, browser type, and use of Flash and Java. We use this information to:

  * ensure that the survey questionnaire is delivered in a form suited to the software your computer is using.
  * assist in providing support to you should you have difficulty accessing or completing a survey.
  * anonymised information is also used for research purposes, for example to determine the percentage of our panelists in a specific country who use a certain type of browser.

With your prior agreement, we may also install advanced cookies or similar code that can identify tags attached to certain web-sites or on-line advertisements relating to our clients and/or their products. Alternatively, again with your prior agreement, we may scan for and read cookies or code installed by other websites that you may have visited. The information obtained in this way will be used to help us send you surveys that are relevant to you (for example, you may be asked your opinion on ads that you've actually seen), or for other research into internet usage.

#### 5\. Use of Digital fingerprinting?

We also use digital fingerprinting technology, also known as "Machine Identification" digital fingerprints, to gather certain information about your computer hardware and software, for example, your IP address, the display settings of your monitor, the type of browser you are using, the type of operating system you are using, etc. This information is sent to our trusted third-party partner who converts it into a unique serial number – the digital "fingerprint" – and determines if it matches previous fingerprints. The data collected in this process and the digital fingerprint created is not tied to any of your personal information, is stored on secured servers, and is only used for quality control purposes and to help prevent panelists from completing the same survey many times, and for no other purpose.

#### 6\. How long will we keep the information you provide?

We will keep the information you provided when you joined our panel, together with any information you provided in response to a recruitment questionnaire for as long as you remain a member of the panel. You can leave the panel at any time you wish. We may also remove you from our panel if you are not taking part in any surveys, are no longer eligible to be a member of any other reason, or the panel is closed. Before removing anyone from our panel, we will contact them to let them know and provide details of how to remain a panel member where appropriate. However, in the event we consider you breach Rewarding Panel’s rules or terms and conditions, Rewarding Panel may remove you from our panel without any notice and your access to the panelist website and to your points account will be closed.

When you leave the panel you will be unsubscribed, or the panel is closed, we will delete all your contact details, together with any other information that could be used to identify you, leaving only anonymous responses to surveys that you participated in.

#### 7\. How can you get access to your information and/or correct it?

You have the right to request a copy of all the information we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please contact our Data Protection Department. They can be contacted by

Email sent to: [panelksa@rewardingpanel.com](mailto:panelksa@rewardingpanel.com)

Or by letter sent to:

> Panel Support Team, Rewarding Panel PO BOX: 71283, Dubai, UAE 

Please quote the name of the panel and your panel membership number (if known) in your email.

#### 8\. How do you ensure my personal information is secure?

We take very seriously our responsibilities to keep your personal information secure. As such, we take every reasonable precaution to ensure your information is protected from loss, theft, or misuse. These precautions include appropriate physical security of our offices, controlled access to computer systems, and use of secure, encrypted internet connections when collecting personal information.

#### 9\. How to contact us

For more information about our panels, panel membership or information related to your membership of one of our panels, please contact our Panel Support Team. They can be contacted by:

Email sent to: [panelksa@rewardingpanel.com](mailto:panelksa@rewardingpanel.com)

Or by letter sent to:

> Panel Support Team Rewarding Panel PO BOX: 71283, Dubai, UAE 

If you have any questions or require further information about our privacy policy, our compliance with data protection laws or information we hold about you, please contact our Data Protection Department. They can be contacted:

By email sent to: [panelksa@rewardingpanel.com](mailto:panelksa@rewardingpanel.com)

Or write to us at:

> Panel Support Team, Rewarding Panel PO BOX: 71283, Dubai, UAE 

Please quote the name of the panel and your panel membership number (if known) in your email.

#### 10\. Changes to our privacy policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review, and we will place any updates on this webpage. We will also inform you of any changes via the news section of the panel members’ website. Our privacy policy was last updated on June 2015.

#### 11\. Useful Link

< World organisation for market research - ESOMAR: [www.esomar.org](http://www.esomar.org/)
